Suppression fire only.
只使用压制火力
We take this one alive.
我们这次抓活的
Tight formation.
密集队形
Don't tell me MECH never considered that
别告诉我 机械党居然看不出来
an open channel distress signal from an injured Decpeticon might be a trap.
受伤的霸天虎在公开频道发出求救信号 可能是个陷阱
I'll bear that in mind next time.
下回我会牢记在心的
Decepticon radio chatter's all abuzz about the workover you gave poor Breakdown.
你对倒霉的打击干的那些事 已经成了霸天虎无线电台的热门话题
As an ex-Con myself,
作为一名前霸天虎成员
I really should have disarrayed you for that!
我真该收拾你一顿！
But, an old acquaintance and her nasty little human destoried my ship and skinned my knee.
不过 一个故交和她的小无赖
I mean to pay them back in kind, both of them.
我一定要以牙还牙 干掉他们
You see.
如你所见
I make it in and out of place as most Decepticons can't,
我比大多数霸天虎更能适应这个鬼地方
but I'm still learning to navigate this planet.
但我毕竟是初来乍到
What's in it for MECH?
机械党能得到什么好处？
I'll let you live.
我会饶你一命
And since you came to collect that "Transformer", was it?
你本想来抢回那个受伤的“变形金刚” 对吗？
I'll throw in whatever is left of Arcee,
我可以把阿尔茜的残骸留给你
after I've broken her.
但是 我要尝鲜
Thanks for walking me home, Jack.
谢谢你送我回家 杰克
You're a real gentleman.
你真有风度
I don't want you reved up before bedtime.
我可不想在睡前听见你发动机的轰鸣
Mom's a light sleeper, and...
妈妈睡觉很轻 而且…
I don't think that she'd understand about...
我想她不会明白…
Understand what, Jack?
明白什么 杰克？
You breaking curfew for the third time this month?
明白这个月你为什么第三次违反宵禁？
Mom.
妈妈？
Or why your boss called about you missing another shifted work?
明白为什么你的老板打电话 说你又没去换班？
Or maybe the email I received from your art-history teacher
还是为什么我收到 你的艺术史老师发来的邮件
who's concerned you've been falling asleep in class?
讨论你上课时睡觉的问题？
Well, two words, mom, art and history.
妈妈 他翻来覆去只说两个词 美术和历史
Tell me the rumors aren't true Jack.
告诉我 那些传言不是真的 杰克
Tell me you're not racing that motorcycle.
告诉我 你没用摩托车去飙车
No, no, wait... Where did you hear that?
不 不 等等…你从哪儿听说的？
Small town, people talk.
这是个小地方 人言可畏
I work in an emergency room, Jack.
我在急诊室工作 杰克
I've seen what can happen.
我可见过飙车的下场
So please, tell me you haven't fallen in with the bad crowd.
求求你 告诉我 你没跟那群坏孩子学坏
What?
什么？
No, no, no, no. My friends are the good crowd.
不 不不 我的朋友们都是好孩子
Seriously good.
好得不能再好了
I let you have that bike because you convinced me you are mature enough to handle it.
我让你留下那辆车 是因为我相信 你已经够成熟了 能掌握分寸
But I think you may need a gentle reminder.
但我认为需要适当提醒你一下
Message received, mom,
信息已查收 妈妈
loud and clear.
铭记在心
I'm glad we had this talk.
这次谈话很受用
I meant,
我是说
let's see if a few weeks without the distraction of your motorcycle will do the trick.
这几个星期不准骑摩托车 看你能不能收心
Eh, but...
但是…
No but! You're grounded from everything but school, and work.
没有但是！除了学校和工作 你哪儿也不许去
And if you want to take a bike to either,
如果你想骑车出去
you'll pedal.
就骑自行车吧
Serious face, Jack.
我是认真的 杰克
If I see that motorcycle out of the garage...
如果我发现摩托车不在车库…
Now, go wash up and get some sleep.
好了 去洗洗睡吧
I love you.
我爱你
I'll miss you while you're grounded.
你被禁足期间 我会想你的
Don't worry Arcee. I'll visit you here every day.
别担心 阿尔茜 我每天都会来看你的
Eh, Jack?
呃 杰克？
I won't be here.
我不能呆在这里
Sitting on my fat tire for two weeks is not an option.
静坐两个星期 我的轮胎肯定会胖死了
No, no, no... You saw mom's serious face.
不不不… 你也看见我妈那副表情了
Well, Arcee, I feel badly enough that I had to lie to her all this time,
阿尔茜 让她一直蒙在鼓里 我已经感觉很愧疚了
but if you're not here,
但如果你不在
she's gonna think that I'm blowing her off.
她会觉得 我把她的话当成耳旁风
Deep breath Jack.
深呼吸 杰克
Your mom works late nights.
你妈妈很晚才下班
I'll try to be back in the garage before she gets home.
我会尽量在她到家之前 回到车库
But... no promises.
但是… 不敢保证
Hey, mom.
嘿 妈妈
Jack, I hope you're not planning to eat take-out tonight.
杰克 你今晚不打算吃外卖吧
I took my break early so I could cook my grounded son a wholesome dinner.
我提前下班了 可以给禁足的儿子做一顿营养晚餐
Oh-organic tofu! Awesome!
哟…有机豆腐！好东西！
Hey, eh, car beats ten-speed. I'll be home soon.
嘿 你肯定比我快 我一会儿就到家
Love you. Bye!
我爱你 再见
Come on, pick up, pick up, pick up.
拜托 快接 快接 快接
Arcee! You wouldn't be in the garage right now?
阿尔茜！你不会没在车库里吧？
Negative, Jack.
我没在 杰克
Can we talk about this later?
我们回头再说行吗？
No. Mom's on her way home.
不行 妈妈正在回家的路上
If you don't race back there right now, I will be grounded for life.
如果你不立刻回家 我就要被禁足一辈子了
And mom will make me sell you for parts.
而且妈妈可能让我把你拆了卖掉
Bee, can you handle it?
小蜂 你能应付吗？
Ratchet, I need to bridge.
救护车 我需要环陆桥
Jack!
杰克！
Jack! I can't believe you disobeyed me.
杰克 你居然不听我的话
Where is the motorcycle?
摩托车呢？
Eh...
呃…
What do you mean?
你在说什么？
She's right where I left her.
我不是把她放在那儿了吗
Did you get one of your crew to sneak it in?
是你让哪个狐朋狗友偷偷送来的
Or did you just walk it up again?
还是你刚刚推进来的？
OK, mom. You really wanna know?
好吧 妈妈 你真的想知道？
Fasten your seatbelt.
做好心理准备
My motorcycle is a sentient robotic organism from a distant planet,
我的摩托车是个有自主意识的机械生命体 来自一颗遥远的星球
part of a team stationed here on Earth,
她的队伍驻扎在地球上
fighting a secret war.
正在打一场秘密战争
And I spent most of my time after school hanging with her crew.
放学后的大部分时间 我都和她的战友呆在一起
Jack...
杰克…
And the coolest thing,
最酷的是
this isn't even her actual form.
这还不是她的真实形态
She's really a giant robot, who can transform into a vehicle.
她其实是个巨大的机器人 可以变成摩托车
Enough, Jack.
够了 杰克
It's OK, Arcee, show yourself.
没事了 阿尔茜 现身吧
She is... She's shy.
她… 她很害羞
Arcee? Really?
阿尔茜？说真的
No more hiding, no more lies.
别再躲了 不用撒谎了
Oh, come on, roll out already!
噢 拜托 出发啊！
So, em,
那么 嗯…
the bad crowd you've been hanging out with is a...
那群和你在一起的坏孩子是…
science fiction club?
科幻俱乐部的？
I have to get back to work,
我要回去工作了
we will continue this when I get home.
等我回家 我们再继续谈
Thanks for the support, "partner".
真是两肋插刀啊 “搭档”
Don't blame me, remember...
别怪我 记住…
I know, I know...
我知道 我知道…
You don't exist.
你不存在
Your ship's black box sustained serious damage in the explosion.
你飞船上的黑匣子 在爆炸中受到严重损毁
But our software was able to reconstruct a few frames from the security thingy.
但我们用软件从安保部件中 恢复了部分画面
That's him.
就是他
My Jack.
我的杰克
Our facial recognition algorithm will send Jack's image across the web--
我们的面部识别算法 会把杰克的图像发到网上
another kind of web.
不是你那种网
Ah... the mother lode.
啊… 有料了
Government database?
政府资料库？
Social networking page.
社交网站
Everything worth knowing about Jack Darby is right here.
所有关于杰克的有用信息都在这里了
Age sixteen, Jasper, Nevada.
十六岁 内华达州贾斯帕市
Mother... June Darby, a nurse.
母亲是… 琼・达比 一名护士
Maybe I'm being too hard on Jack,
或许我对杰克太苛刻了
but he lied.
可是他撒谎
And the only way he's gonna learn is if I stick to my...
要让他吸取教训 我只能坚持…
Arcee, is mom home yet?
阿尔茜 我妈回来了吗？
I didn't see her car.
我没看见她的车
Don't know.
不知道
I just bridged from base to beat her here.
我也是赶在她之前 从基地传送过来
Oh, and there's a package for you.
哦 那儿有你的一个包裹
Hello, Jack.
你好 杰克
Silas.
塞拉斯
What is it? What's going on?
这是什么？怎么回事？
MECH.
机械党
They know where I live?
他们连我住哪儿都知道？
We know things about your family that even you don't know.
我们对你家人的了解 更胜于你
For example, do you know where your mother is?
比如 你知道你妈妈身在何处吗？
What did you...
你做了什么…
Understand, Jack. We have no intention of hurting her.
要知道 杰克 我们不打算伤害她
In fact, we'd like to reunite the two of you as soon as possible.
事实上 我们更乐意让你们母子俩尽快团聚
I just need you and Arcee to follow the GPS coordinates programmed into this communicator.
只要你和阿尔茜 跟着这个通讯器内置的GPS坐标
They'll lead you to the temporary facility I've set up.
它会带你们来到我的临时军营
Ratchet...
救护车…
Arcee?
阿尔茜！
Did I not mention our communicator scrambles the signal and your brains?
我是不是忘了说 我们的通讯器 能扰乱联络信号和你的大脑？
Any break in communication or attempt to reach the other Autobots,
无论是破解通讯 还是企图联系其他汽车人
and Miss Darby... Well,
达比小姐就会…那个…
I wouldn't want to feel responsible for the outcome.
发生什么后果 我可概不负责
If anything happens to her because of my connection to all this, I...
如果因为我被牵扯进来 导致她发生意外 我…
Jack, MECH is only interested in me.
杰克 机械党只对我感兴趣
Once they get what they want,
他们一旦如愿以偿
they'll let your mom go.
就会放了你妈妈
That's not exactly reasuring.
这怎么能让我安心
You're family, too.
你也是我的家人
So... What's the plan?
那么… 怎么办？
The usual.
老办法
Mom?
妈妈？
Looking for June?
是在找琼吗？
She's hanging around here somewhere.
她就在附近某个地方挂着呢
Airachnid!
毒蜘蛛！
What's she doing here?
她怎么来了？
Help them, please.
帮帮他们 求你了
They are humen like you!
他们和你一样 是人类
You can't let Airachnid...
你不能让毒蜘蛛…
A few human lives are a small price to pay for a miracle of science like yourself.
几条人命不值一提 你才是我们想要的科学奇迹
Arcee...
阿尔茜
You and I will have a private session later.
一会儿我要和你私下里谈谈
Promise.
我保证
Gentlemen.
先生们
I'm still learning about human kind,
我对人类还不完全了解
but one thing is clear to me, Jack.
但有件事我很清楚 杰克
You people care deeply about family.
你们人类对于家人格外关心
Therefore, the sweetest revenge I could possibly devise
因此 我能想到的最有爱心的复仇手段
would be to make you watch as I take your family apart.
莫过于让你亲眼看我如何让你家破人亡
If you hurt my mother,
如果你敢伤害我妈妈
- I...
- 我…
- You remember how much I enjoy sport,
- 你应该记得我很喜欢赛跑
don't you, Jack?
对吧 杰克？
So I'll give you the opportunity to save your mother.
所以 我要给你个机会去救你妈妈
I've stashed her close by.
我把她藏在了这附近
If you can rescue her before the stroke of twelve,
如果你能在十二点的钟声响起前救下她
I will let both of you go unharmed.
我就把你们俩完璧归赵
Deal?
成交吗？
And if I can't?
如果我做不到呢？
What do you think?
你认为呢？
Please, don't let her do this.
求求你 别让她这么做
You can let us go. We won't tell anyone.
你放我们走 我们谁都不说
Enough.
够了
Yes, Jack.
没错 杰克
Man up already.
要像个男子汉
Six minutes.
六分钟
Mom? Mom!
妈妈 妈妈！
Now, I know we promised the spider-bot that she would have first crack at you,
虽然我们答应那个蜘蛛人 由她给你开第一刀
but something tells me she plans to turn our mutual crisscross...
但是我有预感 她不再打算借刀杀人…
... into a double-cross.
而是想一箭双雕
Silas, we don't have the means of transporting it right now.
塞拉斯 我们现在没法把它运走
We'll have to cut and run.
那我们只能见好就收了
Open her up.
切开她
Mom!
妈妈！
Jack?
杰克？
Jack, what are you doing here?
杰克 你怎么来了？
Who are these people?
这些人是谁？
How did I get in this, this... stuff.
我怎么跑到…这里面了？
Don't worry, mom. I'm gonna get you out.
别担心 妈妈 我会把你弄出来的
Jack, the robots are real?
杰克 那些机器人都是真的吗？
I beat your deadline!
我提前完成了！
'fraid not, Jack.
恐怕没有 杰克
The task wasn't for you to find your mother by mid-night.
在午夜找到你的妈妈还不算数
You had to rescue her.
你必须救下她
And time's up!
但时间到了
Now.
现在
Take a seat, sit back,
乖乖地坐在一边
and enjoy the horror show.
欣赏恐怖表演吧
Make haste, gentlemen.
快点儿 先生们
And don't worry about making a mess.
弄乱一点没关系
You know, Jack.
说起来 杰克
She is your mom.
她是你的妈妈
Why should I have all the fun?
我为什么要独享快乐呢？
So you get to choose, agonizing, or excruciating?
选择权给你 是痛苦难耐 还是痛不欲生？
No, no!
不 不！
Jack, your mother wants to know.
杰克 你妈妈想知道答案
Don't leave her "dangling".
别吊她的胃口喔
You monster. Stop this!
你这怪物 住手！
We only have time to take one part.
时间只够取出一个部件
Go straight for the heart.
直接拿走心脏
Let her go.
让她走
No matter the outcome, the spoils will be ours.
不管谁赢谁输 残骸都是我们的
Well, Jack. If you won't decide,
杰克 如果你还举棋不定
I guess it's lady's choice.
我想就得由女士来选择了
Mom, I'm sorry.
妈妈 对不起
No!
不！
Jack, your motorcycle?
杰克 是你的摩托车吗？
I can explain, mom.
我会解释的 妈妈
Wait, I already did.
等等 我已经解释过了
MECH lost Breakdown.
机械党放跑了打击
What were the odds they can't hold on to you?
可他们连你都看不住吗？
No! Jack!
不！杰克！
Mum!
妈妈！
Jaaaaack!
杰克――！
Ah, Jack!
啊 杰克！
Hang on, June.
坚持住 琼
Aim for the creepy crawling.
瞄准那个大爬虫
How did they find us?
他们是怎么找到这儿的？
You can let us go. We won't tell anyone.
你放我们走 我们谁都不说
Thanks for coming, Agent Fowler.
多谢相救 福勒探员
If I'd known Con were involved, I would have called in Prime.
早知道还有虎子 我就该叫擎天柱来
That might have been too much for mom to handle in one night.
恐怕我妈一夜之间 受不了那么多刺激
Ah! Not again!
啊！又来这套！
No!
不！
So that's how it's done. Genius.
原来是这样的 太有才了
Mrs Darby,
达比夫人
I'm special agent William Fowler.
我是特工威廉・福勒
It's time you knew the truth.
该让你知道真相了
For the past several months, Jack's been... interning for me at the agency.
近几个月 杰克一直…在我处实习
Agent Fowler, mom's not gonna buy it.
福勒探员 我妈是不会买账的
He's got that right.
他说对了
Agent Fowler.
福勒探员
Let me guess-- without a trace?
让我猜猜――什么都没留下？
Uhh!
哼！
And she would be your...
那么 她是你的…
Motorcycle, guardian, Autobot, friend.
摩托车 保镖 汽车人 朋友
Call me Arcee.
叫我阿尔茜好了
Thank you, Arcee.
谢谢你 阿尔茜
I think it's time for that ride you once made me promise.
看来我可以兑现诺言 带你去兜风了
Mom, meet my science fiction club.
妈妈 这就是我的科幻俱乐部